Guide to the Secular Yiddish Schools in North America Collection M0732
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Yiddish school files
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Feb 1930. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Jun-July 1935. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Jun-July, Dec 1936. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Jan, Aug-Sept, Dec 1937. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Nov 1938. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Feb, Mar, May, Aug-Sept 1939. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Feb, May 1941. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Jan, Apr 1942; Jun-Jul, Oct 1945; Feb, Apr 1947; Nov 1949. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    Kinder Zhurnal, May, Dec 1950; Jan, Feb, Mar, Apr, Dec 1951; Jan, Feb 1952. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Feb, Mar, Apr, Oct 1955; Jan, Mar, Apr 1956; Jan, Feb, Apr, Oct 1957. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Feb, Apr 1958. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Jan, Mar, Apr 1959; Jan, Feb, Apr, Dec 1960. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Jan, Feb, Mar, Apr, Dec 1961. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Jan, Feb, Mar, Apr, Oct 1962. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Feb, Mar, Apr, Oct, Dec 1963. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Mar 1964; Mar, Apr, Dec 1965; Feb, Mar, Apr, Oct, Dec 1966. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Jan, Dec 1967; Jan 1968; Mar-Apr 1969; Apr, May, Oct, Dec 1970. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder Zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    Kinder Zhurnal, Jan, Apr 1971; Fall 1973; Win 1974, Spr 1975; Spr 1978; Fall 1979. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Yearbooks, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Yerlekher alamanakh. SA Shul 1, 115 East 169th St., Bronx, NY. Undated, ca. mid-1930s. Original, in Yiddish and English.
  - Yearbooks, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Four yearbooks. SA Shul 1, 115 East 169th St., Bronx, NY. 1938, 1973, 1944, and 1947. Originals, in Yiddish and English.
  - Yearbooks, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    Four yearbooks. Sholem Aleichem Folkshul 21, Bronx, NY. 1950, 1966, 1967, 1968. Originals, in Yiddish and English.
  - Yearbooks, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    Two yearbooks. Sholem Aleichem Folkshul 21, Bronx, NY. 1970, 1971. Originals, in Yiddish and English.
  - Yearbooks, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    Shul zhurnal. Sholem Aleichem Folkshul 15, Brooklyn, NY. 1937. Original, in Yiddish and English.
  - Yearbooks, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    Four yearly almanacs. Sholem Aleichem Folkshul 15, Brooklyn, NY. 1950, 1956, 1958, 1959. Originals, in Yiddish and English.
  - Yearbooks, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    Five yearbooks. Sholem Aleichem Folkshul 15, Brooklyn, NY. 1963, 1964 (2 copies), 1965, 1966, 1969. Originals, in Yiddish and English.
  - Letterhead, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    One sheet personal letterhead and 2 sheets letterhead, Shalom Aleichem Folk Institute, ca. 1960s. Originals, in English and Yiddish
  - newspaper clipping, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    Newspaper article. Religyeze veltikhkeyt, fun Sh. Margoshem. Der Tog, May 7, 1967. Article about Saul Goodman's work. Photocopy, in Yiddish.
  - newsletters, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    Three bulletins. SA Folk Institute, NY. Jan. and Oct., 1950, originals, in Yiddish. March, 1953, original, in English.
  - pamphlets, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    Two pamphlets. Camp Boiberik, Lectures and Diaglogues 1972 and Entertainment; Camp Boiberik, Lectures and Dialogues 1973 and Entertainment. English and Yiddish, originals.
  - reprints, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    Two reprints. Saul Goodman, The Future of the American Jewish Secular School. The Reconstructionist. May 29, 1964. Original, in English. Saul L. Goodman, Jewish Secularism in America--Permanence and Change. Judaism: A Quarterly Journal of Jewish Life and Thought. Vol. 9, no. 4, Fall 1960. Original, in English.
  - Souvenir journals, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    Dorem shvalvn: Zhurnal un program tsum may kontsert fun der norfolker arbeter ring shul (Norfolk, VA). Two issues: May 1929 and May 1930. Originals, in Yiddish and English.
  - Anniversary observance, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    Anniversary journal. 20 yor geto oyfshtand 15 yor medines yisroel. April 1963. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Newsletters, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    Shul News, v. 2 no. 1. Parent newsletter, Sholem Aleichem Shul 21, Bronx, NY. Original, in English. Nov. 1949. Constitution and by-laws of the Parent Teacher Association of Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul 21. Original, in English. Undated, ca. 1949.
  - Oneg Shabbes songs, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    Oneg Shabbes lider. Sholem Aleichem Folk Institute, NY. Contains 1 p. Oneg shabbes program. Feb. 1953. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Yiddish Teachers Seminar, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    Yidisher lerer seminar. Pedagogical materials. Originals, in Yiddish. 1950s and 1970s.
    Pedagogical Materials
  - Yiddish Teachers Seminar bulletin, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    Yidisher lerer seminar un folks-universitet. 154-156 East 70th Street, New York 21, NY. 41-ster lern-yor buletin [academic bulletin]. Original, in Yiddish. 1958-59.
  - Graduir zhurnal, 1935-36; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    SA Shul 45 Graduir Zhurnal 1935-1936. Original.
    Souvenir Journals; Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Correspondence, 1980s-1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    Four letters from Esther Codor Cohen to Hinde Freedman, 1980s and 1994.
    Personal Correspondence; Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Memoirs, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Memoir, handwritten in Yiddish. Undated.
    Memoirs: Published and Unpublished; Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Memoirs, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1930s-1980s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Correspondence to Esther Codor Cohen from the 1930s-1980s. Handwritten and typed, originals, in Yiddish.
  - Commemorative certificates, circa 1970s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Certificates commemorating tree plantings and other donations in honor of Esther Codor Cohen's late brother, Ephraim Codoroff, and late husband Meyer Cohen. Originals, ca. 1970s, English and Yiddish.
    Rituals and Lifecycle Events; Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Correspondence, 1990; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    Correspondence relating to Esther Codor Cohen memory book project. Yiddish and English, originals and photocopies. 1990.
  - Memoirs, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    Memoirs by Alice Woll, Richard Codor, Jacob Katzman, Joe Schwartzman, Diana Woll-Zurer, Esther Brooks, Charlotte Shalita Scheiner, Lyvia Shaefer, Robert J. Woll, Norman Jaffe, Seymour Margolin, Jean Woll, Reuven Woll, Anne and Murray Merling, Blanche and Peretz Milbauer, Hinde Schutzman Friedman, and Chana Schachner for Esther Codor Cohen memory book project. Yiddish and English, photocopies. 1989-1990.
  - Correspondence, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    Correspondence and other materials pertaining to Esther Codor Cohen memorial committee. Yiddish and English, 1990.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Photographs, 1930s-1980s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    Photographs for Esther Codor Cohen memory book. Originals, 1930s-1980s.
    Photographs.; Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Newsletters, 1989; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    Newsletters and correspondence relating to Esther Codor Cohen memorial committee. English and Yiddish, 1989.
    Administrative / Organizational Materials; Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Souvenir journals, 1935; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    SA Shul 45 Yerlekher shul zhurnal li-khoved di: graduirndike. In Yiddish, original, 1935.
  - Memory book, 1990; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    Memories of Esther: dedicated to the lasting memory of the Yiddish teacher Esther Codor Cohen a"h. The Esther Codor Cohen Memorial Committee: Gella Schweid Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Chana Schachner and Lyvia Schaefer. 131 p. Paste-up copy, Yiddish and English, original, 1990.
    Tributes and Anniversary Celebrations; Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Obituaries, 1987; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    Obituary notices for Esther Codor Cohen, 1987. Originals and photocopies in Yiddish and English.
    Obituaries; Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Correspondence, 1990-1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    Correspondence regarding Esther Codor Cohen memorial committee.
  - Memoirs, 1988-89; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    Recollections of Esther Codor Cohen for memory book. Handwritten in English and Yiddish, 1988-1989. Originals and photocopies.
  - Memoirs, 1983; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    Account of meeting with Esther Codor Cohen in Tel Aviv, Israel, by Gella Schweid Fishman. Handwritten, in Yiddish, 1983.
  - Obituary, 1973; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    Eulogy for Meir Cohen z"l by M. Helmish. Yiddish, photocopy, 1973.
  - Memoirs, 1988-89; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    Memoirs submitted for the Esther Codor Cohen memory book. Handwritten and typed, in English and Yiddish, originals and photocopies. 1988-1989.
  - Correspondence, 1988-89; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    Correspondence pertaining to Esther Codor Cohen memorial committee.
  - Obituaries, 1991; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    Di Tsukunft, vol. 96 no. 2 May-June 1991. Heshbon, no. 117, Spring 1991. Both contain articles about Esther Codor Cohen.
  - Photographs, 1930s-1980s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    Photographs of Esther Codor Cohen and those who knew her. Originals and photocopies. 1930s to 1980s.
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    Correspondence regarding Esther Codor Cohen Memorial Committee. Yiddish and English, originals and photocopies. 1988-1989.
    Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Protokol bukh, 1937-1939; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    Protokol bukh. Notebook containing handwritten meeting minutes regarding SA Yungt Klub activities in which Esther Codor Cohen participated. Original, in Yiddish. 1937-39.
  - Protokol bukh, 1939-1941; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    Protokol bukh. Notebook containing handwritten meeting minutes regarding SA Yugnt Klub activities in which Esther Codor Cohen participated. Original, in Yiddish. 1939-41.
  - Protokol bukh, 1939-1941; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Protokol bukh, 1941; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    Protokol bukh. Notebook containing handwritten meeting minutes regarding SA Yugnt Klub activities in which Esther Codor Cohen participated. Original, in Yiddish. 1941.
  - Protokol bukh, 1951-1952; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    Protokol bukh. Notebook containing handwritten meeting minutes regarding SA Yugnt Klub activities in which Esther Codor Cohen participated. Original, in Yiddish. 1951-52.
  - Diary, 1977; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    Diary of Esther Codor Cohen. Original, Yiddish, 1977.
    Biographical Material; Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Bank passbooks, 1967-1976; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    3 passbooks from The New York Bank for Savings. 1967-1976. Originals, in English.
  - Bank statement, 1986; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    Fragment of bank statement from Bank Leumi le-Israel. Original, in English. 1986.
  - Photographs, 1988; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    Photographs taken at memorial service held for Esther Codor Cohen on Jan. 17, 1988, in New York City. Prints, negatives, and photocopies. Forverts article reporting the event: "Ester Kodor-Kohen a"h." Jan. 29, 1988, photocopy, in Yiddish.
  - Postcards, 1940s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    Picture postcards, some written to Esther Codor [Cohen]. 1940s and undated.
  - Memory book, 1976; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    Memory book given to Esther Cohen from former students, ca. 1976.
  - Photographs, 1939-1940s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    Class photographs with teacher Esther Cohen. 1939 and ca. 1940s.
  - Yunge shtimen, 1940; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    Yunge shtimen, no. 1, June 1940. Publication written and published by students at SA Folkshul 45.
    Student Writings: Published and Unpublished; Cohen, Esther Codor
  - Videnkol, 1938; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    Videnkol, vol. 2 no. 1, 1938. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Graduation journals, 1937-1940; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    Graduation journals, SA Folkshul 45, 1745 Monroe Avenue, Bronx, NY. 1937, 1938, 1939, 1940. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Graduation journals, 1941-44; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    Graduation journals, SA Folkshul 45, 1745 Monroe Avenue, Bronx, NY. 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Graduation journals, 1949-1954; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    Graduation journals, SA Folkshul 45, 233 East 174th St., Bronx, NY. 1949, 1950-51, 1954. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Di Shpilers, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    Publicity regarding Di Shilers Yiddish Community Theater. Undated ca. 1990s, in English and romanized Yiddish.
  - Memoir, 2003; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    One page memoir by August Maymudes. Photocopy, in English. 2003.
    Memoirs: Published and Unpublished; Maymudes, August
  - Study of Yiddish, 1951; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    Revyu boygens: Review sheets for study of Yiddish grammar. Original, in Yiddish. 1951.
    Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Language; Maymudes, August
  - Teaching application, 1950; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    Application and related correspondence for teaching position. Originals, in Yiddish, 1950.
    Administrative / Organizational Materials; Max Dunetz
  - Newspaper clippings, 1978; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    Newspaper clippings. Yiddish, photocopies, 1978; 1990s.
    School Publicity: Newspaper Clippings; Max Dunetz
  - Memoir, 1990s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    Memoir, typed and handwritten, in Yiddish. Photocopy, ca. 1996. 2 p.
    Memoirs: Published and Unpublished; Max Dunetz
  - Newspaper clipping, 1952; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    Forverts clipping depicting SA Mitlshul Class of '52. July 13, 1952. Original, in Yiddish and English.
  - Photograph, 1950s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    Photograph depicting Parents Board at Workmen's Circle School 15, 1775 (?) Bryant Ave., Bronx, NY, ca. 1950s. Invitation to graduation celebration at the Wynnefield Yiddishe Folkshul, 5353 Gaynor Road. In Yiddish and English, original, 1951. Accompanied by note to Gella Schweid Fishman from Libby Okun Cohen, dated 2003. Original, in Yiddish.
    Photographs.; Libby Okun Cohen
  - WC Shul 7 pamphlet, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    Give your child a Jewish education: Pamphlet advertising WC School 7, 154 West Tremont Ave., Bronx, NY. Original, in English and Yiddish. Undated, ca. 1950s.
  - 1946, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    Fertsenter (14th) tsuzamenfor fun di arbeter ring shuln. Pamphlet, in Yiddish, original, 1946.
  - School meeting postcard, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    Form postcard inviting parents to meetings at the Crown Heights Arbeter Ring Shul 1, 1411 Lincoln Place, Brookly 13, NY. Original, undated ca. 1950, in Yiddish.
  - Publications, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    Yungvarg, vol. 1, no. 1 (May 1937); vol. 4, no. 4 (Apr. 1941); vol. 7, no. 4 (Dec. 1944); vol. 8, no. 1 (Jan. 1945); vol. 10, no. 4 (Apr. 1947); no. 4 (Oct. 1963).
  - Programs, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    Confirmation program, Jewish Community of Cortlandt Sunday School, Cortlandt, New York, 1960. JCC Star, Sunday School Newspaper Club, Dedicated to the Sunday School confirmands of 1960. 10th Annual promotion-graduation concert and secular bar-bas mitzvah ceremonies program, Parkway Jewish School, 1962. Graduation program, Los Angeles Mittelshule, June 20, 1964.
    Rituals and Lifecycle Events
  - Correspondence, 1964-1965; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    Two letters from Lena Kornfeld, coordinator of Los Angeles Jewish Children's Schools. June 23, 1964 and Feb. 5, 1965. Originals, in English.
    Personal Correspondence; Goldberg, Itche
  - Administrative materials, 1954-1964; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    Administrative materials relating to Los Angeles Kinder Shules. Originals, in English.
    Administrative / Organizational Materials; Lena Kornfeld
  - Mollie Goodman, 1962; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    Clipping from New York Teacher News, 3 obituary notices for Mollie Goodman, wife of teacher and author Henry Goodman. Original, English, Feb. 10, 1962.
    Obituaries; Henry Goodman
  - Promotional materials, 1950s-1980s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    Pamphlets and information sheets promoting various Suburban Jewish Schools. English, originals, 1950s to 1988.
  - Newsletters, 1959-1963; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    Newsletters from the Valley Kindershule, 7551 Laurel Canyon, North Hollywood, CA and the Asher Levy Jewish School, 246 Scherer Blvd., Franklin Square, Long Island. English, originals, 1959-1963.
  - 1960-1973, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    Pamplet, The Dr. Chaim Zhitlowsky Foundation for Jewish Secular Education, original, English and Yiddish, undated ca. 1960. Protokol fun der gezelshaftlekher konferents li-toyves progresiv-veltlekher dertsyung. Original, Yiddish, 1962. Service Bureau of Education announcement of Continuation Committee meeting. Original, English, 1962. Congress for Jewish Culture, katalog - 1973. Original, Yiddish.
  - Anniversary observances, 1957, 1963; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    Valley Kinder Shule announcement for annual closing concert and barbecue. Original, English, 1957. In ondenk fun der varshaver geto: program un materieln 1943-1963. Aroysgegebn fun farlag kinderbukh in yidishe dertsyung byuro (New York). Original, Yiddish, 1963.
  - Teacher Bulletin, 1944; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    Shul un kultur komisye fun der idisher sektsye [IWO]: Lerer buletin 1943-1944. Original, in Yiddish. Program outline - Tennage [teenage] group. Sample monthly program. Original, undated.
  - Press release, 1963; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    Press release from Service Bureau of Jewish Education announcing that a wire of condolence was sent on Nov. 28, 1963 to Mrs. Jaqueline Kennedy.
  - Yungvarg, 1937-1942; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    Yungvarg: vol. 1, no. 3 (Sept. 1937); vol. 1, no. 7 (Feb. 1938); vol. 2, no. 1 (Nov. 1938); vol. 2, no. 3 (Feb. 1939); vol. 4, no. 3 (Mar. 1941); vol. 5, no. 3 (Apr. 1942).
  - 1938, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 13)
    Two article clippings: Fartifn un farbesern, I. Goldberg, Proletarishe dertsiyung, Sept.-Oct. 1938. Tsu der geshikhte fun idishn shul-vezn in amerike, K. Marmor, Proletarishe dertsiyung, Jan., 1938. Originals, in Yiddish.
    School Publicity: Newspaper Clippings; Itche Goldberg
  - Photograph, 1946-1947; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 14)
    Class picture with teacher. 1946-1947 Haym Solomon Shule. Original, ca. 1947.
  - Diploma, 1950s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 15)
    Blank diploma. North Shore Jewish Sunday School. English and Yiddish, original, undated ca. 1950s.
    Diplomas, Report Cards, Graduation Announcements & Certificates; Itche Goldberg
  - Purim, 1950s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 16)
    Purim materials from various schools. Originals, in Yiddish and English, ca. 1950s.
  - Informational materials, 1950s-1960s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 17)
    Informational pamphlets and materials from various schools. Originals, in English, ca. 1950s and 1960s.
  - Newsletter, 1957; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 18)
    Valley Kindershule newsletter, vol. 3, no. 3 (Dec. 1957). Original, in English.
  - 1961, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 19)
    Report to Workshop, May 6, 1961, by I. Goldberg: report on status quo of Jewish secular education. Original, in English.
    Informational Material: History, Philosophy, Curriculum of Schools; Itche Goldberg
  - Calendar, 1956-57; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 20)
    Israel picture calendar, 1956-1957. English and Hebrew, original.
  - Yearbook, 1949; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 55, Folder 21)
    19-ter yubili Sholem Aleichem Folkshul 21, 3301 Bainbridge Ave., Bronx, NY. Original, in Yiddish and English, 1949.
  - Newsletters, 1959-1966; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    Newsletters and informational materials from various Suburban Jewish schools. Originals, in English, 1959-1966.
  - Newsletters, 1965; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    Shalom: Cooperative Jewish School of Greater Washington, vol. 11, no. 1 (Oct. 1965). Original, in English.
  - Newsletters, 1968; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    Shalom, vol. 5 no. 28. Revista infantil editada por el consejo central de educacion israelita (vaad hajinuj) de la A.M.I.A. Original, in Hebrew, Yiddish, and Portuguese.
  - Curriculum, 1960-1970; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    Asher Levy Jewish School synopsis of lessons. 4 p., photocopies, in English.
  - Holidays, 1959; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    Asher Levy Jewish School materials for Purim, Chanukah, and Passover. Photocopies, in English.
  - Examinations, 1959; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    History examinations. Originals, English and Yiddish, 1959 and undated.
  - Play scripts, 1959; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    Scipt for school play, The Opatshu Presentation. 3 p., photocopy, undated, in romanized Yiddish.
  - Play scripts, 1969; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    Scipts for two summer camp plays, The Alef-Beys Quarrel and Discovery, 2969. Photocopies, in English and romanized Yiddish, 1969.
  - IWO, 1955; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    Statement of the dissolution of the commitee for progressive Jewish education. Photocopies, in English, 2 p., ca. 1955.
  - Bible stories, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 56, Folder 10)